<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Subho Sankar Banerjee</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Subho Sankar Banerjee</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nuclear Particle Transport Simulation</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/nudy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/nudy/</guid><description>The project aimed at developing a framework to read and process data available in the Evaluated Nuclear Data File (ENDF) format for use in Monte-Carlo techniques for the simulation of accelerator driven fission machines, and of the related fuel cycle. We explored (1) development of a common and robust data format to be used with both high energy nuclear cascade and low energy neutron transport codes/libraries; and (2) developing fast-yet-accurate sampling techniques for multi dimensional probability distributions to be used in the simulation of the fission machines.</description></item><item><title>AliEn: The ALICE Environment</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/alien/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/alien/</guid><description>The AliEn project is a Grid middleware solution which offers transparent access to distributed computing and storage resources all over the world and constitutes the primary production environment for simulation, reconstruction, and analysis of physics data of the ALICE experiment at CERN. In 2010, AliEn was deployed on more than 85 sites all over the world which contributed more than 30,000 compute nodes and 200PB of storage.
My work on the AliEn project involved (1) identifying vulnerabilities in the file access protocol, and (2) implementing a user authorization mechanism to resolve the discovered vulnerabilities, and (3) on just in time job and data assignment using pilot jobs to intelligently make decisions of job assignment based on data locality.</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Vehicle Resilience</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/av/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/av/</guid><description>The emergence of ML-driven systems and their ubiquitous adoption means that their trustworthiness and dependability are now of paramount importance. Autonomous vehicle (AV) technologies are the perfect examples of such systems and are advertised to be transformative, with the potential to improve traffic congestion, safety, productivity, and comfort. With the increasing popularity and ubiquitous deployment of AVs on public roads, dependability, and trustworthiness have increasingly become critical requirements for public acceptance and adoption.</description></item><item><title>Intelligence Augmented Compter Systems</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/learnedsystems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/projects/learnedsystems/</guid><description>Computer systems are rapidly evolving to meet the computational demands of emerging application demands by incorporating innovations in hardware architecture, operating systems, network interconnects, and storage, leading to increased heterogeneity. The state of the art is to vertically integrate these systems with painstakingly built, handcrafted, average-case heuristics. Heuristic generation is already a fundamental challenge, as variations across machine configurations, workloads, and deployment environments can make heuristic generation painful and costly. Moreover, we are reaching the limits of conventional approaches of generating heuristics, which involve recurring human-expert-driven engineering efforts.</description></item></channel></rss>