<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications on Subho Sankar Banerjee</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on Subho Sankar Banerjee</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Is Function-as-a-Service a Good Fit for Latency-Critical Services?</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/wosc2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/wosc2021/</guid><description>Function-as-a-Service (FaaS) is becoming an increasingly popular cloud-deployment paradigm for serverless computing that frees application developers from managing the infrastructure. At the same time, it allows cloud providers to assert control in workload consolidation, i.e., co-locating multiple containers on the same server, thereby achieving higher server utilization, often at the cost of higher end-to-end function request latency. Interestingly, a key aspect of serverless latency management has not been well studied: the trade-off between application developers’ latency goals and the FaaS providers’ utilization goals.</description></item><item><title>Improved GPU Implementations of the Pair-HMM Forward Algorithm for DNA Sequence Alignment</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/iccd2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/iccd2021/</guid><description>With the rise of Next-Generation Sequencing (NGS) technology, clinical sequencing services become more accessible but are also facing new challenges. The surging demand motivates developments of more efficient algorithms for computational genomics and their hardware acceleration. In this work, we use GPU to accelerate the DNA variant calling and its related alignment problem. The Pair-Hidden Markov Model (Pair-HMM) is one of the most popular and compute-intensive models used in variant calling.</description></item><item><title>BayesPerf: Minimizing Performance Monitoring Errors Using Bayesian Statistics</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/asplos2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/asplos2021/</guid><description>Hardware performance counters (HPCs) that measure low-level architectural and microarchitectural events provide dynamic contextual information about the state of the system. However, HPC measurements are error-prone due to non determinism (e.g., undercounting due to event multiplexing, or OS interrupt-handling behaviors). In this paper, we present BayesPerf, a system for quantifying uncertainty in HPC measurements by using a domain-driven Bayesian model that captures microarchitectural relationships between HPCs to jointly infer their values as probability distributions.</description></item><item><title>Live Forensics for HPC Systems: A Case Study on Distributed Storage Systems</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/sc2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/sc2020/</guid><description>Large-scale high-performance computing systems frequently experience a wide range of failure modes, such as reliability failures (e.g., hang or crash), and resource overload-related failures (e.g., congestion collapse), impacting systems and applications. Despite the adverse effects of these failures, current systems do not provide methodologies for proactively detecting, localizing, and diagnosing failures. We present Kaleidoscope, a near real-time failure detection and diagnosis framework, consisting of of hierarchical domain-guided machine learning models that identify the failing components, the corresponding failure mode, and point to the most likely cause indicative of the failure in near real-time (within one minute of failure occurrence).</description></item><item><title>FIRM: An Intelligent Fine-Grained Resource Management Framework for SLO-Oriented Microservices</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/osdi2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/osdi2020/</guid><description>Modern user-facing, latency-sensitive web services include numerous distributed, intercommunicating microservices that promise to simplify software development and operation. However, multiplexing compute-resources across microservices is still challenging in production because contention for shared resources can cause latency spikes that violate the service-level objectives (SLOs) of user requests. This paper presents FIRM, an intelligent fine-grained resource management framework for predictable sharing of resources across microservices to drive up overall utilization. FIRM leverages online telemetry data and machine-learning methods to adaptively (a) detect/localize microservices that cause SLO-violations, (b) identify low-level resources in contention, and (c) take actions to mitigate SLO-violations by dynamic reprovisioning.</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning for Load Balancing in the Linux Kernel</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/apsys2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/apsys2020/</guid><description>The OS load balancing algorithm governs the performance gains provided by a multiprocessor computer system. The Linux&amp;rsquo;s Completely Fair Scheduler (CFS) scheduler tracks process loads by average CPU utilization to balance workload between processor cores. That approach maximizes the utilization of processing time but overlooks the contention for lower-level hardware resources. In servers running compute-intensive workloads, an imbalanced need for limited computing resources hinders execution performance. This paper solves the above problem using a machine learning (ML)-based resource-aware load balancer.</description></item><item><title>Inductive-bias-driven Reinforcement Learning for Efficient Schedules in Heterogeneous Clusters</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/icml2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/icml2020/</guid><description>The problem of scheduling of workloads onto heterogeneous processors (e.g., CPUs, GPUs, FPGAs) is of fundamental importance in modern data centers. Current system schedulers rely on application/system-specific heuristics that have to be built on a case-by-case basis. Recent work has demonstrated ML techniques for automating the heuristic search by using black-box approaches which require significant training data and time, which make them challenging to use in practice. This paper presents Symphony, a scheduling framework that addresses the challenge in two ways: (i) a domain-driven Bayesian reinforcement learning (RL) model for scheduling, which inherently models the resource dependencies identified from the system architecture; and (ii) a sampling-based technique to compute the gradients of a Bayesian model without performing full probabilistic inference.</description></item><item><title>ML-driven Malware that Targets AV Safety</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2020/</guid><description>Ensuring the safety of autonomous vehicles (AVs) is critical for their mass deployment and public adoption. However, security attacks that violate safety constraints and cause accidents are a major deterrent to achieving public trust in AVs which hinders a vendors' ability to deploy the AVs. Creating a security hazard that results in a serious safety compromise (for example, an accident) is compelling from an attacker&amp;rsquo;s perspective. In this paper, we introduce an attack model, a method to deploy the attack in the form of a smart malware, and experimental evaluation of its impact on production grade autonomous driving software.</description></item><item><title>ML-based Fault Injection for Autonomous Vehicles: A Case for Bayesian Fault Injection</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2019/</guid><description>The safety and resilience of fully autonomous vehicles (AVs) is of significant concern, as exemplified by several headline making accidents. While AV development today inherently involves verification, validation and testing, end-to-end assessment of AV systems under accidental faults in realistic driving scenarios is largely unexplored. This paper presents DriveFI, a machine learning-based fault injection engine, which can mine situations and faults that maximally impact AV safety, demonstrated on two industry-grade AV technology stacks (from NVIDIA and Baidu).</description></item><item><title>Towards a Bayesian Approach for Assessing Fault Tolerance of Deep Neural Networks</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2019_bdlfi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2019_bdlfi/</guid><description>This paper presents Bayesian Deep Learning based Fault Injection (BDLFI), a novel methodology for fault injection in neural networks (NNs) or more generally differentiable programs. BDLFI uses (1) Bayesian Deep Learning to model the propagation of faults, and (2) Markov Chain Monte Carlo inference to quantify the effect of faults on the outputs of a NN. We demonstrate BDLFI on two representative networks and find that our results challenge pre-existing results in the field.</description></item><item><title>AcMC²: Accelerated Markov Chain Monte Carlo for Probabilistic Models</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/asplos2019/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/asplos2019/</guid><description>Probabilistic models (PMs) are ubiquitously used across a variety of machine learning applications. They have been shown to successfully integrate structural prior information about data and effectively quantify uncertainty to enable the development of more powerful, interpretable, and efficient learning algorithms. This paper presents AcMC², a compiler that transforms PMs into optimized hardware accelerators (for use in FPGAs or ASICs) that utilize Markov chain Monte Carlo methods to infer and query a distribution of posterior samples from the model.</description></item><item><title>CAUDIT: Continuous Auditing of SSH-Servers To Mitigate Brute-Force Attacks</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/nsdi2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/nsdi2019/</guid><description>This paper describes CAUDIT, an operational system deployed at the National Center for Supercomputing Applications (NCSA) at the University of Illinois. CAUDIT is a fully automated system to enable the identification and exclusion of hosts that are vulnerable to SSH brute-force attacks. Its key features includes: 1) a honeypot for attracting SSH-based attacks over a /16 IP address range and extracting key-metadata (e.g., source IP, password, SSH-client version, or -key) from these attacks; 2) executing audits on the live production network by replaying attack attempts recorded by the honeypot; 3) using the IP addresses recorded by the honeypot to block SSH attack attempts at the network border using a Black Hole Router (BHR) while significantly reducing the load on NCSA&amp;rsquo;s security monitoring system; and 4) informing peer sites of attack attempts in real-time to ensure containment of coordinated attacks.</description></item><item><title>ASAP: Accelerated Short Read Alignment on Programmable Hardware</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/tc2018/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/tc2018/</guid><description>The proliferation of high-throughput sequencing machines ensures rapid generation of up to billions of short nucleotide fragments in a short period of time. This massive amount of sequence data can quickly overwhelm today&amp;rsquo;s storage and compute infrastructure. This paper explores the use of hardware acceleration to significantly improve the runtime of short-read alignment, a crucial step in preprocessing sequenced genomes. We focus on the Levenshtein distance (edit-distance) computation kernel and propose the ASAP accelerator, which utilizes the intrinsic delay of circuits for edit-distance computation elements as a proxy for computation.</description></item><item><title>A ML-based Runtime System for Executing Dataflow Graphs on Heterogeneous Processors</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/socc18/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/socc18/</guid><description>This paper briefly describes the design a system that addresses the challenge of scheduling distributed data-analytics workloads on heterogeneous processing fabrics (which include CPUs, GPUs, FPGAs and ASICs) in cloud-based, dynamic, multi-tenant environments. To demonstrate the capabilities of the proposed system, we use a computational genomics workflow that addresses the growing need for rapid genomic analyses in hospital environments.</description></item><item><title>Hands Off the Wheel in Autonomous Vehicles? A Systems Perspective on over a Million Miles of Field Data</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2018/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2018/</guid><description>Autonomous vehicle (AV) technology is rapidly becoming a reality on U.S. roads, offering the promise of improvements in traffic management, safety, and the comfort and efficiency of vehicular travel. The California Department of Motor Vehicles (DMV) reports that between 2014 and 2017, manufacturers tested 144 AVs, driving a cumulative 1,116,605 autonomous miles, and reported 5,328 disengagements and 42 accidents involving AVs on public roads. This paper investigates the causes, dynamics, and impacts of such AV failures by analyzing disengagement and accident reports obtained from public DMV databases.</description></item><item><title>AVFI: Fault Injection for Autonomous Vehicles</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2018_avfi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/dsn2018_avfi/</guid><description>Autonomous vehicle (AV) technology is rapidly becoming a reality on U.S. roads, offering the promise of improvements in traffic management, safety, and the comfort and efficiency of vehicular travel. With this increasing popularity and ubiquitous deployment, resilience has become a critical requirement for public acceptance and adoption. Recent studies into the resilience of AVs has shown that though the AV systems are improving over time, they have not reached human-levels of automation.</description></item><item><title>Symphony: Leveraging Probabilistic Graphical Models to Schedule Tasks to Clusters of Heterogeneous Processors</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/aisys2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/aisys2017/</guid><description>The diminishing returns from Moore&amp;rsquo;s law and technology scaling have significantly driven the deployment of a plethora of accelerators in large scale computing infrastructures. While the design of such accelerators is being broadly addressed, the challenge of designing an intelligent scheduler that achieves optimizes performance while abstracting low-level systems details for the heterogeneous processing fabric from the programmer continues to be a major problem. An important application where the foregoing challenges come together is computational genomics, particularly the &amp;ldquo;Variant-Calling and Genotyping Analysis.</description></item><item><title>On Accelerating Pair-HMM Computations in Programmable Hardware</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/fpl2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/fpl2017/</guid><description>This paper explores hardware acceleration to significantly improve the runtime of computing the forward algorithm on Pair-HMM models, a crucial step in analyzing mutations in sequenced genomes. We describe 1) the design and evaluation of a novel accelerator architecture that can efficiently process real sequence data without performing wasteful work; and 2) aggressive memoization techniques that can significantly reduce the number of invocations of, and the amount of data transferred to the accelerator.</description></item><item><title>Data-Driven Longitudinal Modeling and Prediction of Symptom Dynamics in Major Depressive Disorder: Integrating Factor Graphs and Learning Methods</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/cibcb2017/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/cibcb2017/</guid><description>This paper proposes a data-driven longitudinal model that brings together factor graphs and learning methods to demonstrate a significant improvement in predictability in clinical outcomes of patients with major depressive disorder treated with antidepressants. Using data from the Mayo Clinic PGRN-AMPS trial and the STAR*D trial for validation, this work makes two significant contributions in the context of predictability in psychiatric therapeutic outcomes. First, we establish symptom dynamics in response to antidepressants by using the forward algorithm on a factor graph.</description></item><item><title>Bringing Innovations in Systems and Analytics to the Bedside: Design of the CompGen Machine</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/eccb2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/eccb2017/</guid><description>We present the CompGen machine, a research computing system built at the UIUC to integrate the analysis of omics, medical sensor, and electronic health record data to provide more precise, personalized and data-driven therapeutics. We demonstrate the efficacy of the machine on several important healthcare problems.</description></item><item><title>ASAP: Accelerated Short Read Alignment on Programmable Hardware</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/fpga2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/fpga2017/</guid><description>The proliferation of high-throughput sequencing machines allows for the rapid generation of billions of short nucleotide fragments in a short period. This massive amount of sequence data can quickly overwhelm today&amp;rsquo;s storage and compute infrastructure. This poster explores the use of hardware acceleration to significantly improve the runtime of short-read alignment (SRA), a crucial step in pre-processing sequenced genomes. It presents the design and implementation of ASAP, an accelerator for computing Levenshtein distance (LD) in the context of the SRA problem.</description></item><item><title>Efficient and Scalable Workflows for Genomic Analyses</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/didc2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/didc2016/</guid><description>Recent growth in the volume of DNA sequence data and associated computational costs of extracting meaningful information warrants the need for efficient computational systems at-scale. In this work, we propose the Illinois Genomics Execution Environment (IGen), a framework for efficient and scalable genome analyses. The design philosophy of IGen is based on algorithmic analysis and extensive measurements on compute- and data-intensive genomic analyses workflows (such as variant discovery and genotyping analysis) executed on high-performance and cloud computing infrastructures.</description></item><item><title>IGen: The Illinois Genomics Execution Environment</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/sc2015/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/sc2015/</guid><description>There has been a great optimism for the usage of DNA sequence data in clinical practice, notably for diagnostics and developing personalized treatments tailored to an individual’s genome. This poster, presents a study of software tools used in identifying and characterizing mutations in a genome. We present IGen, a runtime framework which executes this workflow as a data-flow graph over a partitioned global address space. Preliminary results on the Blue Waters supercomputer show that IGen is able to accelerate single node performance (alignment - 1.</description></item><item><title>Decomposing Genomics Algorithms: Core Computations for Accelerating Genomics Analyses</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/tr2014/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/tr2014/</guid><description>Technological advances in genomic analyses and computing sciences has led to a burst in genomics data. With these advances, there has also been parallel growth in dedicated accelerators for specific genomic analyses. However, biologists are need of a re-configurable machine that can allow them to perform multiple analyses without needing to go for dedicated compute platforms for each analysis. This work addresses the first steps in the design of such a re-configurable machine.</description></item><item><title>Two dimensional correlated sampling using alias technique</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/acat2012_rng/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/acat2012_rng/</guid><description>Monte-Carlo sampling of two dimensional correlated variables (with non zero covariance) has been carried out using an extended alias technique which was originally proposed by A. J. Walker to sample from an one dimensional distribution. Although, the method has been applied to a correlated two dimensional Gaussian data sample, it is quite general and can easily be extended for sampling from a multidimensional correlated data sample of any arbitrary distribution.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing the AliEn Web Service Authentication</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/acat2011_auth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/acat2011_auth/</guid><description>Web Services are an XML based technology that allow applications to communicate with each other across disparate systems. Web Services are becoming the de facto standard that enable inter operability between heterogeneous processes and systems. AliEn2 is a grid environment based on web services. The AliEn2 services can be divided in three categories: Central services, deployed once per organization; Site services, deployed on each of the participating centers; Job Agents running on the worker nodes automatically.</description></item><item><title>Securing the AliEn File Catalogue - Enforcing authorization with accountable file operations</title><link>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/acat2011_lfn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ssbaner2.cs.illinois.edu/publications/acat2011_lfn/</guid><description>The AliEn Grid Services, as operated by the ALICE Collaboration in its global physics analysis grid framework, is based on a central File Catalogue together with a distributed set of storage systems and the possibility to register links to external data resources. This paper describes several identified vulnerabilities in the AliEn File Catalogue access protocol regarding fraud and unauthorized file alteration and presents a more secure and revised design: a new mechanism, called LFN Booking Table, is introduced in order to keep track of access authorization in the transient state of files entering or leaving the File Catalogue.</description></item></channel></rss>